Aakansha Sahay

Counselor

Address - A/603, Jangid Estate, Mira Road East, Thane

Phone - 9284085572

Email - aakansha725@gmail.com

Objective

Caring counselor with more than one year of experience in conducting one to one counseling sessions . Proficient in preparing and maintaining detailed session on life skills and guidance. Strong public speaking and NET Qualified in Psychology. Life skills trainer with a year of experience providing a wide variety of individual, group and familial counseling techniques and interventions strategies.

Skills

- Social skills teacher
- Mentoring
- Strong public speaker
- Individual and group counseling
- Motivational speaking
- Psychosocial Assessment
- Mental Health Evaluations
- Lecturer, Psychology
- Interpersonal skills
- Empathy
- Counseling

Work History

Nov 2015 to Jul 2018

Software Tester

Tata Consultancy Services, Nagpur, Maharashtra

- Evaluated software for functionality, from and usability.
- Performed load and database testing
- Create accurate and efficient tests scripts to manage automated testing of certain products and features
- Collaborated with developers and product owners to stay current on product features and intended functionality.

Aug 2018 to Feb 2019

Mental Health Counselor and Life Skills Trainer

Self Employed, Nagpur, Maharashtra

- Conducted life skills sessions in schools and mentored students for social skills
- Conducted psychometric tests on clients and recommended necessary interventions.
- Developed goal-oriented psych educational and activity therapy groups to improve student's level of functioning.
- Led educational seminars and lectures at schools to expand awareness of mental health symptoms and issues.
- Applied array of different methodologies to assist clients with therapy.

Education

Feb 2017 to Feb 2019

Master of Arts: Counseling Psychology, IGNOU- Nagpur

Sep 2011 – Sep 2015

B.Tech in Civil Engineering, Orissa Engineering College, Bhubaneswar

Accomplishment

- **NET Qualified in Psychology** with 98.28 percentile in June, 2019.
- Public speaker, Mentor as member of Toastmasters International Club